<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="HELP_STRING_1">Android Sea Merchant</string>
    <string name="HELP_STRING_2">Shir Ben Israel</string>
    <string name="HELP_STRING_3">Version 2.0</string>
    <string name="HELP_STRING_4">
        The trading week begins! You are a sea merchant who sails in the Mediterranean. \n
        In one week you can trade local goods. \n
        Your goal is to end this week with amount of money hig as possible. \n
        Watch out for dangers! \n
        Good luck! \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_5">How to play?</string>
    <string name="HELP_STRING_6">
    When game starts you will see the option window. At the top of the screen you will see
        the current day of the week, the current hour and the current state.
        You will be able to go to the market to buy and sell goods, to sail to one
        of the neighbour states, to visit the bank or to sleep until tomorrow.
        If your ship is damaged, you will also be able to fix it.
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_7">
        Pressing on each of the relevant buttons will open a window to perform the action you
        have selected. Each of those action (except sleeping) will increase the game clock.
        Sleeping until tomorrow will move you to 6:00 of next morning.
        The game will be finished at the end of the seventh day.
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_8">Market</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_9">
        The numbers on the buttons represents your inventory.
        Pressing on one of the goods button (Wheat, Olives and Copper) will open the
        market window where you can buy and sell the goods you have selected.
        The price for tonne appears in the center of the main window, where each state has
        different prices for each goods.
        You will be able to use only cash (and not what it the bank) to buy goods.
        You will be able to buy goods until 23:00 at the night.
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_10">
    \nAll buys and sells in one state takes one hour together.\n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_11">Sailing</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_12">
        Pressing on one of the flags of the different states will leads you to the sailing window
        to sail to the selected state. \n
        The green numbers of the flags represents the sail durations to the possible destinations. \n
        You will be able to sail into 5 ports in the game: \n
        Egypt, Israel, Turkey, Cyprus and Greece. \n
        Standard sailing takes 3 hours. \n
        Sailing between Egypt and Turkey or Cyprus and Greece takes 6 hours. \n
        Greece is accessible only from Cyprus. You can start sailing until 20:00 at evening and
        if you want to sail to a long sail that takes 6 hours then you must start sail until 17:00. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_13">Bank</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_14">
        You can deposit your money in the bank to protect it from robbers. Each bank visits on one
        state to deposit or to draw money takes one hour together. \n
        Night deposition (deposit and then go to sleep) gives 10% interest. \n
        You can deposit money in the bank in one state and then draw it in another state. \n
        You can visit bank until 23:00 at night. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_15">Sleep until tomorrow</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_16">
        At the end of a trading day you need to go to sleep until the next trading day. \n
        At the start of each day the prices of the goods will be fixed again. \n
        The start of each trading day is at 6:00 and its end is at any time you want until 24:00. \n
        Pressing on the sleeping button will progress the time to next day 6:00 in the morning \n.
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_17">Fix ship</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_18">
        If the ship is damaged, you can fix it in this window for a price. Each fix takes
        one hour. \n
        You can fix the ship until 23:00. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_19">Sailing</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_20">
        In this window you can chose how many guard ships to rent to next sail and that start sailing.
        You will be able to see the expected dangers and the price of the guard ships (which depends
        on the value of your goods and cash and the expected dangers). \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_21">See events</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_22">Shoal</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_23">
        If you start sailing at 17:00 or later, your ship may runs aground. \n
        When this happen, the ship will be damaged. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_24">Storm</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_25">
        If you sail in a storm, the high waves can wash goods out of your ship and even create damage
        to the ship. \n
        When a storm is developed, you will get a message about it the start of the trading day. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_26">Winds</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_27">
        If you sail in high winds, they may cause your ship to deviate from its course and
        return to where it came from. \n
        On winds danger you will get a message on the start of the trading day. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_28">Fog</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_29">
        If you try to ship into a state which its port is in a fog you may get
        a message that you cannot get close into the beach and you will have to turn
        back and sail to the place you came from. \n
        You will get a message at the start of the trading day in case of a fog on one port. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_30">Sinking</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_31">
        If you overload the ship with too much goods, over its capacity, you are taking a risk that
        it would start sinking in the middle of the see. \n
        If that happens, you will have to throw some of the goods into the see to save the ship. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_32">Sail with broken ship</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_33">
        If the ship has a small damage and you decided to sail without fixing it first,
        the sailing can increase the damage. When damage is more that square of ship capacity you
        will not be able to ship until it is being fixed. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_34">Pirates</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_35">
        Your ship may encounter pirates on every voyage. In that case you have 3 options: \n
        You can negotiate the pirates and offer them some of your goods and cash, so  hopefully they will
        not attack you. \n
        The more you offer them, the less likely they are to attack you. \n
        Escape: You can try to escape. As far as the ship
        Yours is less loaded in relation to your capacity,
        so the chances of you escaping will increase. \n

        Attack: If you have guard ships, it may be worth to attack the bandits yourself.
        The more guard ships you have the greater your chance of winning a battle.
        You can rent the guard ships before you set sail.
        The price of the ships depends on the value of the goods and cash on the ship and the
        predicted weather damage. \n

        If you defeat the bandits in battle, you may find treasure on their ship.
        If not, you will take their ship captive, thus increasing the capacity of your ship. \n

        During the battle your ship may be damaged. \n

        If you lose a battle with the robbers, they will steal some of your property or cash,
        and also cause great damage to the ship. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_36">Abandoned ship</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_37">
        Your ship may encounter an abandoned ship halfway. In that case,
        You can drag it to a safe shore and take the goods on it. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_38">Start day events</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_39">
    At the beginning of each trading day (except the first),
    after the weather announcement, one of the following will happen:
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_40">Increase / decrease in price</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_41">
    The price of one of the goods will increase or decrease drastically in one of the states\n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_42">Fishing Boat</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_43">
    A fishing boat will collide with your ship and damage it. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_44">Meeting with a trader</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_45">
    Another trader will want to sell or buy goods from you.
        This deal will not take you time You can decide if you want to do it or give it up. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_46">Increase ship capacity</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_47">
    In that case, you can increase the ship\'s capacity for a certain amount of cash or goods. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_48">Fire</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_49">
    A fire breaks out in your warehouses and consumes some of the goods.
        Because of this, keeping property on the ship overnight is a risk. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_50">Strike</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_51">
        The ship\'s crew threatens to strike, and will agree to return to work only in exchange for
        some of the cash and goods on the ship. \n
        You can offer them a compromise: \n
        If accepted, you can continue working as usual. \n
        If it is rejected, it will lose two working days during negotiations
        and the search for a new crew. \n
        You can also fire the crew immediately and go look for a new team for
        the price of one working day. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_52">End trading week</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_53">
    After seven days, trading will end. Your score will be equal to the amount of cash you have,
        in addition to the amount of money in the bank, in addition to the value of the goods on the ship,
        in the country you are in, less the value of the damage caused to the ship. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_54">Medals</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_55">
    During the game you can win medals for reaching certain goals.
        For example, earn a certain amount of money, or defeat the pirates in battle.
        Some of the medals will give you a bonus that will affect the next games. \n
    </string>
</resources>

