<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="HELP_STRING_1">Android Sea Merchant</string>
    <string name="HELP_STRING_2">Shir Ben Israel</string>
    <string name="HELP_STRING_3">Version 2.0</string>
    <string name="HELP_STRING_4">
        The trading week begins! You are a sea merchant who sails in the Mediterranean. \n
        In one week you can trade local goods. \n
        Your goal is to end this week with amount of money hig as possible. \n
        Watch out for dangers! \n
        Good luck! \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_5">How to play?</string>
    <string name="HELP_STRING_6">
    When game starts you will see the option window. At the top of the screen you will see
        the current day of the week, the current hour and the current state.
        You will be able to go to the market to buy and sell goods, to sail to one
        of the neighbour states, to visit the bank or to sleep until tomorrow.
        If your ship is damaged, you will also be able to fix it.
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_7">
        Pressing on each of the relevant buttons will open a window to perform the action you
        have selected. Each of those action (except sleeping) will increase the game clock.
        Sleeping until tomorrow will move you to 6:00 of next morning.
        The game will be finished at the end of the seventh day.
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_8">Market</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_9">
        The numbers on the buttons represents your inventory.
        Pressing on one of the goods button (Wheat, Olives and Copper) will open the
        market window where you can buy and sell the goods you have selected.
        The price for tonne appears in the center of the main window, where each state has
        different prices for each goods.
        You will be able to use only cash (and not what it the bank) to buy goods.
        You will be able to buy goods until 23:00 at the night.
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_10">
    \nAll buys and sells in one state takes one hour together.\n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_11">Sailing</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_12">
        Pressing on one of the flags of the different states will leads you to the sailing window
        to sail to the selected state. \n
        The green numbers of the flags represents the sail durations to the possible destinations. \n
        You will be able to sail into 5 ports in the game: \n
        Egypt, Israel, Turkey, Cyprus and Greece. \n
        Standard sailing takes 3 hours. \n
        Sailing between Egypt and Turkey or Cyprus and Greece takes 6 hours. \n
        Greece is accessible only from Cyprus. You can start sailing until 20:00 at evening and
        if you want to sail to a long sail that takes 6 hours then you must start sail until 17:00. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_13">Bank</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_14">
        You can deposit your money in the bank to protect it from robbers. Each bank visits on one
        state to deposit or to draw money takes one hour together. \n
        Night deposition (deposit and then go to sleep) gives 10% interest. \n
        You can deposit money in the bank in one state and then draw it in another state. \n
        You can visit bank until 23:00 at night. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_15">Sleep until tomorrow</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_16">
        At the end of a trading day you need to go to sleep until the next trading day. \n
        At the start of each day the prices of the goods will be fixed again. \n
        The start of each trading day is at 6:00 and its end is at any time you want until 24:00. \n
        Pressing on the sleeping button will progress the time to next day 6:00 in the morning \n.
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_17">Fix ship</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_18">
        If the ship is damaged, you can fix it in this window for a price. Each fix takes
        one hour. \n
        You can fix the ship until 23:00. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_19">Sailing</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_20">
        In this window you can chose how many guard ships to rent to next sail and that start sailing.
        You will be able to see the expected dangers and the price of the guard ships (which depends
        on the value of your goods and cash and the expected dangers). \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_21">See events</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_22">Shoal</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_23">
        If you start sailing at 17:00 or later, your ship may runs aground. \n
        When this happen, the ship will be damaged. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_24">Storm</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_25">
        If you sail in a storm, the high waves can wash goods out of your ship and even create damage
        to the ship. \n
        When a storm is developed, you will get a message about it the start of the trading day. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_26">Winds</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_27">
        If you sail in high winds, they may cause your ship to deviate from its course and
        return to where it came from. \n
        On winds danger you will get a message on the start of the trading day. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_28">Fog</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_29">
        If you try to ship into a state which its port is in a fog you may get
        a message that you cannot get close into the beach and you will have to turn
        back and sail to the place you came from. \n
        You will get a message at the start of the trading day in case of a fog on one port. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_30">Sinking</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_31">
        If you overload the ship with too much goods, over its capacity, you are taking a risk that
        it would start sinking in the middle of the see. \n
        If that happens, you will have to throw some of the goods into the see to save the ship. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_32">Sail with broken ship</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_33">
        If the ship has a small damage and you decided to sail without fixing it first,
        the sailing can increase the damage. When damage is more that square of ship capacity you
        will not be able to ship until it is being fixed. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_34">Pirates</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_35">
        Your ship may encounter pirates on every voyage. In that case you have 3 options: \n
        You can negotiate the pirates and offer them some of your goods and cash, so  hopefully they will
        not attack you. \n
        The more you offer them, the less likely they are to attack you. \n
        Escape: You can try to escape. As far as the ship
        Yours is less loaded in relation to your capacity,
        so the chances of you escaping will increase. \n

        Attack: If you have guard ships, it may be worth to attack the bandits yourself.
        The more guard ships you have the greater your chance of winning a battle.
        You can rent the guard ships before you set sail.
        The price of the ships depends on the value of the goods and cash on the ship and the
        predicted weather damage. \n

        If you defeat the bandits in battle, you may find treasure on their ship.
        If not, you will take their ship captive, thus increasing the capacity of your ship. \n

        During the battle your ship may be damaged. \n

        If you lose a battle with the robbers, they will steal some of your property or cash,
        and also cause great damage to the ship. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_36">Abandoned ship</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_37">
        Your ship may encounter an abandoned ship halfway. In that case,
        You can drag it to a safe shore and take the goods on it. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_38">Start day events</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_39">
    At the beginning of each trading day (except the first),
    after the weather announcement, one of the following will happen:
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_40">Increase / decrease in price</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_41">
    The price of one of the goods will increase or decrease drastically in one of the states\n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_42">Fishing Boat</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_43">
    A fishing boat will collide with your ship and damage it. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_44">Meeting with a trader</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_45">
    Another trader will want to sell or buy goods from you.
        This deal will not take you time You can decide if you want to do it or give it up. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_46">Increase ship capacity</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_47">
    In that case, you can increase the ship\'s capacity for a certain amount of cash or goods. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_48">Fire</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_49">
    A fire breaks out in your warehouses and consumes some of the goods.
        Because of this, keeping property on the ship overnight is a risk. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_50">Strike</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_51">
        The ship\'s crew threatens to strike, and will agree to return to work only in exchange for
        some of the cash and goods on the ship. \n
        You can offer them a compromise: \n
        If accepted, you can continue working as usual. \n
        If it is rejected, it will lose two working days during negotiations
        and the search for a new crew. \n
        You can also fire the crew immediately and go look for a new team for
        the price of one working day. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_52">End trading week</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_53">
    After seven days, trading will end. Your score will be equal to the amount of cash you have,
        in addition to the amount of money in the bank, in addition to the value of the goods on the ship,
        in the country you are in, less the value of the damage caused to the ship. \n
    </string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_54">Medals</string>

    <string name="HELP_STRING_55">
    During the game you can win medals for reaching certain goals.
        For example, earn a certain amount of money, or defeat the pirates in battle.
        Some of the medals will give you a bonus that will affect the next games. \n
    </string>

    <string name="STATISTICS_INFO">On this page you will find information about the odds of all the events in the game. \n
    \n
    Prices \n
Copper prices in Israel, Turkey, Cyprus and Egypt will usually be between 2500 and 3500 and in multiples of 100. \n
Olives prices in Israel, Turkey, Cyprus and Egypt will generally be between 350 and 650 and in multiples of 50. \n
Wheat prices in Israel, Turkey, Cyprus and Egypt will generally be between 35 and 70 and in multiples of 5. \n
Goods prices in Greece will be according to the same formula, except that they will be multiplied by 1.5 or divided by 1.5 and will always be multiplied by 10. \n
    \n
Weather \n
Every day, except the first, there is a 50% chance that dangerous weather will develop in one of the countries\n
\n
Special event at the beginning of the day \n
The chance of the possibility to increase the ship is 1/6 if you have more than 5000 in cash or goods on the ship. If there is not enough money or goods the chance passes to the possibility of a special price of goods. \n
The chance of meeting a merchant is 1/6 if you have more than 4500 in cash or goods on the ship. If there is not enough money or goods the chance goes to the option for a special price of goods. \n
The chance of a fishing boat colliding is 1/6. \n
The probability of a particularly high price of goods is 1/6. \n
The probability of a particularly low price of goods is 1/6. \n
The chance of a strike is 1/6 if you have goods on the ship or cash and it is not Friday yet. Otherwise the chance goes to fire if you have goods on the ship. Otherwise the chance goes to a special price. \n
    \n
Special price \n
The highest possible price for copper is between 3600 and 4500 in multiples of 100. \n
The highest possible price for olives is between 700 and 800 in multiples of 50. \n
The highest possible price for wheat is between 75 and 90 in multiples of 5. \n
The lowest possible price for copper is between 1500 and 1900 in multiples of 100. \n
The lowest possible price for olives is between 200 and 300 in multiples of 50. \n
The lowest possible price for wheat is between 20 and 30 in multiples of 5. \n
The above prices are valid for Turkey, Israel, Cyprus and Egypt but not for Greece. \n
\n
Damage in collision with a fishing boat \n
Damage can reach up to one-fifth of the smallest of: \n
1. The capacity of your ship squared. \n
2. The value of your ship (cash + bank + the value of the goods in the state where you are located. \n
\n
Increasing ship capacity \n
The type of payment will be from the goods whose value (double quantity price) is the highest, or cash if the cash is worth more than the goods on the ship. \n
The amount of the payment will be a random number between 1 and the maximum amount on the selected payment\n
The magnification will be a sum of two random numbers: \n
A random number between 1 and the maximum amount of copper you are able to purchase according to the value of the ship now. \n
2. A random number between 25 and 124. \n
The magnification will be multiplied by 25. \n
\n
Meeting with a trader\n
If you have goods on the ship then you can sell it to him. If you have no goods you can buy goods from him. \n
The trader\'s bid for copper will be between 2000 and 4000 in multiples of 100. \n
The trader\'s bid for olives will be between 250 and 800 in multiples of 50. \n
The trader\'s bid for wheat will be between 20 and 75 in multiples of 5. \n
The trader will want to buy all the goods you have of a certain type. He will randomly select from the goods on the ship. \n
The amount of goods the trader will offer you for sale is random between 1 and the amount your cash allows you to buy. \n
\n
Fire \n
The fire will consume one type of goods - the one you have at most in the ship\'s warehouses. \n
The quantity consumed will be random between 1 and half the quantity of the goods. \n
\n
Strike \n
The ship\'s crew will agree to a compromise that will give them a random sum worth up to one third of the ship\'s property value and the cash in your possession. \n
\n
Sailing \n
Each voyage can have one of the following events: \n
\n
Overload \n
A random number will be selected between 0 and the amount of goods on the ship. If this number is greater than the allowable capacity the ship will begin to sink.
You will have to throw a random number between 1 and the excess weight into the sea. The type of goods will be the one that weighs more. This process can be repeated several times, until the ship stops sinking. \n
\n
Damage increased \n
If you sail when the ship is damaged and not repaired, you risk increasing the damage. The game will generate a random number between 0 and the capacity of the ship squared.
If a third of this number is less than the damage already done to the ship, then it will cause further damage. The size of the additional damage will be a random number between 0 and the existing damage.
In any case, such damage can only be caused if no drowning has occurred as a result of overload. \n
\n
Abandoned ship \n
If there was no sinking or damage, then there is a 1/9 chance of finding an abandoned ship.
On the abandoned ship you will find at random one of the goods, whose total value will be between 0 and the value of the goods on your ship. \n
\n
Winds\n
If there was no sinking or damage, and there are winds in the state of source or at the destination of the voyage, then there is a 1/3 chance that the ship will make a mistake on its way, and return to the source state. \n
\n
Storm \n
If there was no sinking or damage, and there is a storm in the country of origin or at the destination of the voyage, then there is a 1/3 chance that the ship will get caught in a storm. \n
If there is goods on the ship, then the storm may (50%) wash out the type of goods that has the most on the ship. \n
The amount of goods lost will be up to half the amount on the ship. \n
If no goods are washed from the ship then it will cause damage at a random value from 100 to the capacity of the ship squared. \n
\n
Shoal\n
If none of the above events have occurred, and the sailing time is 5pm or later, then there is a 1/3 chance of getting on the shore.
The damage to the ship is between 100 and the capacity of the ship squared. \n
\n
Pirates \n
There is a 1/3 chance of meeting pirates. \n
The chance of escaping from the robbers is small the loaded the ship is. The game will generate a random number between 0 and the capacity. If this number is greater than the amount of goods on the ship, then you will be able to escape the bandits. \n
The chance of defeating the bandits in battle with 0/1/2/3/4/5 guard ships is 1/51/76/88/94/97 percent respectively. \n
In victory in battle there is a 50 percent chance of taking the pirate ship worth and a 50 percent chance of finding treasure on the ship. When the pirate ship is taken in value, the ship\'s capacity increases by a random number between 25 and the original capacity, in multiples of 25. \n
When a treasure is found on the ship, its value will be a random number between 0 and 1/3 of the ship\'s value. \n
There is a chance that depends on the number of guard ships, which will damage the ship, even though you won the battle. The more guard ships you have, the less likely you are.
The value of the damage is random between 0 and 1/5 for the capacity of the ship squared. \n
If you lose the battle, the robbers will steal from you one of the goods on the ship or the money on it. They can steal up to half the amount of goods or cash on the ship. In addition, the robbers will cause damage to the ship that is between 100 and the capacity of the ship squared. \n
If you offer the robbers a compromise, an offer that will satisfy them will be a random number between 0 and half the ship\'s value, not including the money in the bank.
\n\n
Fog \n
If there is fog in the destination of the voyage, then there is a 50 percent chance that you will be forced to return to the source state, regardless of everything that happened or did not happen on the way. \n
\n
Guard ships \n
The price of each guard ship is 2% of the value of the ship, not including the money in the bank, but at least 50. You can rent up to 5 guard ships for each voyage. \n
Any special weather at the cruise destination will increase the price of the guard ship by 50%. \n
A storm at the destination of the voyage or in the source state will additionally double the price of the guard ship 2. \n
Winds in the country of origin will increase the price of the guard ship by 50%. \n
Sailing from 17:00 onwards will increase the price of the guard ship by another 25%. \n
</string>

</resources>

